
> @redblobgames/mapgen4@2.0.0 test
> node scripts/test.mjs

✔ Coriolis turns eastward perturbations south in the north, reverses with spin, and drag dissipates speed (0.9727ms)
✔ uniform temperature produces no perturbation; heat contrasts drive bounded, persistent winds (5.2313ms)
✔ authored altitude alone causes no pressure-potential force, including the radiation-scale cap (1.3588ms)
✔ wind-driven ocean memory spins up gradually, conserves heat, preserves uniform water and cannot cross dry cells (5.3462ms)
✔ evolving circulation resumes and rolls back exactly with its water and energy budgets (846.3936ms)
✔ tiny-radius, fast retrograde winds stay bounded; fully frozen ocean carries no heat (2.2936ms)
✔ temperature forcing reverses Coriolis by hemisphere and spin and wraps the meridian (1.8448ms)
✔ unforced atmospheric memory decays faster over land without advancing at pause (0.5205ms)
✔ ocean memory has a five-day response and reverses gradually after wind reversal (0.5978ms)
✔ one dry or frozen cell blocks its incident heat transfers while wet closed loops keep heat (1.2529ms)
✔ an empty liquid ocean applies no current or heat transport but retains dynamic memory (0.6739ms)
✔ paused and restored ocean diagnostics use the same stable transport bound as a physical step (0.5217ms)
✔ a generated zero-inventory ocean develops wind memory without applied ocean currents (314.6392ms)
✔ reference climate has latitude bands at zero elapsed time and reproduces exactly (9.8096ms)
✔ tilt/season swap hemispheres; highlands cool and ocean moderates seasonal response (20.7098ms)
✔ generated wind has trade/westerly/polar directions and responds to season/retrograde (3.9762ms)
✔ windward terrain receives more initial rain than its lee and inputs are not mutated (1.4699ms)
✔ reference fields are finite under extremes and runtime starts immediately without spending time (155.3521ms)
✔ vector winds transport vapor north/south conservatively across seams with a stable bound (109.3905ms)
✔ generated highland climate evolves with finite temperatures, energy and water budgets (7521.8761ms)
✔ frozen inventories belong to the conserved water budget and restore together (3.9413ms)
✔ coupled runtime generates frozen mass at zero age and conserves enthalpy while evolving (405.6204ms)
✔ freezing releases fusion energy; melting consumes it and respects finite stores (0.5284ms)
✔ snowmelt becomes downhill discharge and keeps the water and energy budgets (0.5177ms)
✔ snowfall stores water and releases vapor and fusion latent heat (0.4522ms)
✔ frozen cover raises albedo and reduces the following absorbed radiation (0.4595ms)
✔ closed ocean gyres redistribute heat conservatively, preserve uniform fields and stop at dry land (0.602ms)
✔ vegetation changes gradually under sustained drought and its checkpoint restores memory (6.7002ms)
✔ coupled fixed steps and acknowledged rollback preserve ice, vegetation, currents and energy (316.747ms)
✔ comparison baselines are independent snapshots and CSV contains actual deltas (91.7521ms)
✔ coupled symmetric oceans keep both generated polar caps and swap with half-year phase (207.1694ms)
✔ generated frozen surface has no stale pre-freeze discharge for erosion capture (52.3952ms)
✔ generated ice with liquid ocean starts at freezing without a first-step phase surge (0.7157ms)
✔ comparison parameter snapshots distinguish albedo feedback experiments (110.7419ms)
✔ uniform dry land is stationary, inputs are copied and invalid values rejected (5.5491ms)
✔ dry hillslope smoothing lowers peaks, raises neighbors and conserves solid volume (3.4192ms)
✔ runoff cuts downhill rock into mobile sediment and all-land retains every solid (12.1231ms)
✔ closed basin sediment settles locally without a carved outlet (0.6201ms)
✔ ocean sediment is retained and coastal sea outlets do not lift solids onto high land (3.3789ms)
✔ fixed steps converge with refinement and restore all history (11.1925ms)
✔ small radius/extreme transport cap work and report only advanced years (4.1553ms)
✔ preview preserves authored ocean and detail, is periodic, finite at poles and exactly reversible (0.5676ms)
✔ nonuniform glacial terrain candidates have one land-weighted height at each pole (0.3625ms)
✔ runtime freezes copied runoff, undoes entire steps and invalidates replaced climate sources (197.3243ms)
✔ snow compaction and finite cold-start ice preserve water mass (4.1189ms)
✔ ice moves down its surface gradient, carries sediment and stays finite without mass loss (1.3547ms)
✔ land-ice melt enters runoff using actual available sensible heat (2.2432ms)
✔ glacial flow and accumulated solid changes checkpoint exactly (1.912ms)
✔ cold-climate ice, surface estimates and erosion continue exactly through JSON and visible rollback (1484.8448ms)
✔ disabling water clears grounded ice display seeds and roundtrips a thermal-only world (102.7259ms)
✔ restoring a saturated ice sheet rejects invented frozen water and fusion energy (98.924ms)
✔ symmetric generated land and sea ice exchange hemispheres with the seasonal phase (118.433ms)
✔ melting the last grounded ice deposits its transported sediment without losing solid volume (1.2843ms)
✔ Earth-scale SI inputs produce published gravity, mass and escape speed (1.2976ms)
✔ doubling physical radius at fixed density scales mass by eight and gravity by two (0.1657ms)
✔ physical altitude is independent of scene radius and artistic mountain height (0.1369ms)
✔ invalid physical and orbit inputs cannot create NaN or infinite derived state (0.4877ms)
✔ solar preset at one AU gives a year, stellar flux and radiation equilibrium independently (0.1763ms)
✔ body sun moves west under prograde spin and north at northern solstice (0.6609ms)
✔ retrograde and synchronous spin preserve a finite sun direction (0.3021ms)
✔ spherical area integration of instantaneous sunlight approaches one quarter of flux (4.663ms)
✔ clock uses elapsed seconds consistently at 30, 60 and 144Hz (0.917ms)
✔ pause, resume, seek and speed changes cannot catch up hidden wall time (0.3692ms)
✔ painting pauses at the presented frame rather than a queued future rotation (0.2078ms)
✔ space view rotates the planet separately from camera while surface view stays fixed (1.1593ms)
✔ rotated terrain hit retains original barycentric data for physical elevation probing (0.5251ms)
✔ a JSON save and reload continues exactly with conserved budgets and geographic cover (1083.9565ms)
✔ complete document preserves comparison baseline and all runtime state (244.9351ms)
✔ weather view preference roundtrips, defaults off for old saves, and rejects invalid switches and snowfall (457.194ms)
✔ older complete v1 worlds without optional terrain routing retain coarse mode (173.7984ms)
✔ invalid files cannot produce a replacement world (531.3332ms)
✔ thermal-only and disabled worlds preserve their state and options (144.848ms)
✔ saving after visible-frame rollback includes flux and compensated budgets from that frame (205.9174ms)
✔ a paused unsupported-spin world preserves its enabled switches without inventing climate (0.9105ms)
✔ seeding snow from exhausted surface and soil stores cannot leave negative roundoff (0.5077ms)
✔ sphere has no boundary and every halfedge closes reciprocally (18.2687ms)
✔ production-density ridge and valley folds do not invert or collapse (212.3831ms)
✔ painting crosses the date line and poles without touching antipodes (1.7603ms)
✔ closed drainage terminates with every triangle visited even without oceans (3.2598ms)
✔ coordinate sampling wraps the meridian and ignores longitude at poles (0.6592ms)
✔ atlas triangles straddling meridian are local on both edges (0.2033ms)
✔ sphere mesh survives a worker structured clone including the last region (2.6762ms)
✔ polar atlas cap has area up to the pole, with the same surface attributes (0.6632ms)
✔ mountain vertices follow their local radial line; oceans stay at sea level (0.5148ms)
✔ sphere radius changes geometry while mountain height and camera stay independent (0.7931ms)
✔ terrain picking returns original surface UV under radial relief and rotated views (0.8237ms)
✔ generation is deterministic, drains without cycles, and produces finite render buffers (391.3398ms)
✔ sea ice stores cold history, melts gradually, and cannot grow outside its bounds (1.0847ms)
✔ generated sea ice closes the annual cycle and varies continuously across date and year boundaries (0.4088ms)
✔ both polar oceans retain generated sea ice through a brief warm season without Play (106.2462ms)
✔ symmetric oceans exchange seasonal sea ice between hemispheres and warm planets can lose it (390.9717ms)
✔ sea ice evolves with fixed solver steps and restores an unpresented future exactly (155.6401ms)
✔ cached geographic height lookup agrees with exhaustive angular neighbors on sparse polar meshes (103.2386ms)
✔ the reported default south-pole highland no longer contains the false 700m notch and snow stripe (369.9567ms)
✔ local terrain sampling resolves polar elevation and updates after painting (24.6063ms)
✔ polar height reconstruction does not turn vertices at different latitudes into alternating meridian stripes (29.3537ms)
✔ climate anomalies interpolate continuously and keep one value at both poles (1.3021ms)
✔ polar cover uses local polar terrain instead of extruding the 73 degree climate ring (66.8864ms)
✔ potential vegetation distinguishes cold, dry, temperate and tropical climates (0.493ms)
✔ seasonal snow changes cover without reclassifying a forest and needs moisture (0.2518ms)
✔ rainless polar land with a short thaw stays barren rather than growing tundra (0.073ms)
✔ annual reference ignores selected date, responds to elevation and water supply, and stays finite (19.8936ms)
✔ surface is available at zero age, preserves the presented frame, and clears with terrain or model (239.1666ms)
✔ generation gate coalesces requests and accepts only the desired revision (0.8778ms)
✔ bake subtracts raw baseline, clamps targets and never mutates source arrays (1.8873ms)
✔ application stores independent copies, repeated application undoes just the layer (0.262ms)
✔ document round trip validates full schema and rejects malformed, oversized and incompatible data (2.5799ms)
✔ real generator reapplies offsets before regions/rivers and undo retains later brushwork (10.0996ms)
✔ closed terrain depressions hold real water until their sill is reached (5.979ms)
✔ rain, melt and evaporation reconcile the partition without a second water inventory (0.7213ms)
✔ nearly drained terrain reservoirs keep the authoritative coarse water nonnegative (149.2112ms)
✔ terrain water checkpoint resumes exact volumes and fluxes independently (0.6441ms)
✔ authored mesh routing remains a conserved partition through climate evolution, rollback and reload (2362.2471ms)
✔ lake shoreline levels follow available volume and sloping terrain (0.385ms)
✔ successive shoreline frames retain water height, wetness, seams and independent render buffers (82.1843ms)
✔ rendered shorelines preserve the triangular storage integral on sloping and tied beds (294.0136ms)
✔ an authored center-to-center valley cannot become an invented ridge dam (3.0813ms)
✔ ocean, dry land and unresolved coastal cells keep their own inventory (0.6181ms)
✔ corrupt fine stores and out-of-network receivers cannot replace routing state (0.6289ms)
✔ a pending restored fine partition cannot silently advance through coarse routing (0.693ms)
✔ thermal cells cover a closed equal-area sphere, including longitude seam (0.9725ms)
✔ daily forcing has correct equator, polar and opposite-season limits (6.3034ms)
✔ diffusion is pairwise conservative and leaves a uniform field unchanged (0.406ms)
✔ terrain classification wraps longitude and fills sparse cells without NaN (0.5027ms)
✔ land responds faster than a water mixed layer to identical forcing (4.3533ms)
✔ fixed steps give identical climate across frame partitions and close energy budget (18.8271ms)
✔ halving stable time step converges over a seasonal transient (18.0375ms)
✔ checkpoint restores temperature, timestamp and energy together (0.8968ms)
✔ thermal bounds reject invalid config and radius scaling controls diffusion stability (2.2518ms)
✔ runtime restores a presented thermal state and rejects unsupported slow spin (110.5346ms)
✔ clock caps solver work without banking hidden catch-up time (0.3073ms)
✔ two unpresented thermal updates cannot replace the acknowledged visible checkpoint (249.0653ms)
✔ clock reports real work limiting at 20fps and clears it on an uncapped update (0.2143ms)
✔ shared terrain sampling uses mean land elevation without averaging in seafloor (0.1881ms)
✔ coupled water clock restores all stores and fluxes after multiple queued updates (774.1021ms)
✔ water shares stable thermal substeps and terrain/config resets its history (186.3692ms)
✔ water columns initialize with finite stores and physical area (4.9227ms)
✔ evaporation draws only from available water and never exceeds solar demand (2.5711ms)
✔ vapor diffusion and zonal drift cross the seam without polar leakage (1.6568ms)
✔ rain fills soil then surface storage, with a closed total budget (0.8837ms)
✔ closed land depressions retain water then spill once their hydraulic head rises (0.5911ms)
✔ all-ocean has no soil or river discharge; all-land cannot invent an ocean sink (20.5259ms)
✔ mixed coast routing conserves its ocean and terrestrial shares (0.7449ms)
✔ a coastal outlet cannot lift water onto its high land fraction (0.5118ms)
✔ discharge is actual transferred volume per second with radius-aware area (1.5083ms)
✔ paired solar-driven water cycle conserves global inventory through many steps (43.412ms)
✔ stable water time step, refinement and checkpoint restore remain coherent (13.4452ms)
✔ cloud proxy and rain/snow display derive from stores and last-step precipitation without mutating them (10.0822ms)
✔ snow diagnostics use the recorded frozen transfer even if latent heat subsequently warms the column (1.3066ms)
✔ precipitation diagnostics distinguish initial estimates, recorded phase and unknown legacy phase (0.4445ms)
✔ local temperature changes cloud proxy at fixed column water; dry and humid bounds remain exact (0.4902ms)
✔ cloud cache follows visible-frame rollback, terrain regeneration, replacement and water shutdown (321.3933ms)
✔ weather texture has shared scalar polar limits and bounded deterministic bytes (2.123ms)
✔ cloud patterns follow conserved moisture transport and exact save restoration (164.2291ms)
ℹ tests 154
ℹ suites 0
ℹ pass 154
ℹ fail 0
ℹ cancelled 0
ℹ skipped 0
ℹ todo 0
ℹ duration_ms 7904.7175
